Come on! That's right, suck it! Zombies!
快点，把这些僵尸都干掉！
This is the future guys. I'm telling 'ya.
同志们，这就是游戏界的未来的发展方向啊
Greeting and welcome to LGR Oddware.
大家好，欢迎来到LGR志异
Where we take a look at the hardware and software that is odd, forgoten and obsolete.
在这里，我们将回顾一些怪异的，被遗忘的怪异软硬件
And wow, today is all three, this is the Thrustmaster Wizzard Pinball Controller.
而今天要介绍的，三个都占了，这就是 Wizzard 弹珠控制器
A set of an addon controller things to put on your PC keyboard,
它可以放在键盘上，并模拟游玩真实弹珠台的体验
to act pinball like a bumper controls.
As well as motion control for tilting the table.
诸如撞击检测，还有侦测倾斜弹珠台的动作
I cannot wait to dive in this thing, this is a supreme oddware.
我等不及要深究这个极其特别的东西了
Is it going to be good.
绝对会很有意思的
So this right here is the Thrustmaster Wizzard Pinball Controller.
好了，这就是 Wizzard 弹珠控制器了
And yes, I recently got this, because uh...
我最近才搞来这台，因为呢
Well, I've been looking for a long, if you could remember.
如果你们还记得的话，我寻找这个东西很长时间了
Way back when I did my video on the full Maxis collection of mine, I said this:
当时我介绍我的Maxis收藏的时候，我说过：
注：Maxis最出名的软件就是模拟城市系列，开源版叫 Micropolis
And with also, this version of it, which is the ...
好的，这张是Thrustmaste Wizzard 弹珠控制器特别冠名版的
Full Tilt! Pinball Wizzard Pinball Controller Edition by Thrustmaster.
Full Tilt! Pinball 游戏光盘
This is just the CD they came packed in with the Wizzard Pinball Controller.
这张光盘随 Wizzard 弹珠控制器附赠
I don't have one of those...
我暂时还没有控制器......
Obviously that have changed
很明显，现在我有了
that I've been on look out for this ever since doing that video.
我在做完那期视频后就一直在找这个
And when I finally got one, completely boxed and a good price,
终于我找到一个盒装的，价格很合适
this is just like the real thing, according to PC GAMER.
PC GAMER杂志介绍说这个可以完全模拟真实弹珠游戏的体验
Oh, so cool.
:-|
It does come with the free version of a Full Tilt! Pinball, published by Maxis.
该控制器附赠 Maxis 发行的 Full Tilt! Pinball 游戏
"Complete Retail Version At No Extra Cost!"
"免费获得完整零售版游戏!"
And yes, it is for Windows 3.x and Windows 95.
当然，该配件是为Windows 3.x和95设计的
So we will be testing that out a little bit.
一会我们测试一下
But yeah, let's just go ahead and take a look at the rest of this packaging,
但是呢，我们来看看包装里还有啥，没啥特别的
where nothing is really cool.
Although, there is an another version of this that I think only came out in the UK.
尽管这玩意还有一个英国特供版，附带 "Royal Flush"游戏
They came packaged with a gamed called "Royal Flush".
And it had a box that look actually a bit like a pinball machine.
包装也和真正的弹珠桌台有几分神似
And that is even cooler than this.
这包装比我手中的耐人多了
So what the freak is this thing?
所以说，介玩意到底似个嘛？
Well, this is made by Thrustmaster,
首先，该产品由 Thrustmaster 制造
注：图马斯特公司生产的赛车模拟器，模拟飞行摇杆价格不菲（至少600元）
The same people that were responsible for doing
他们也知道很多其他的东西，主要是游戏摇杆
a whole ton of stuff, mainly joysticks.
Like the excellent F-16 flight stick.
诸如备受赞誉的F-16模拟飞行杆
This thing retailed for 39.95,
本弹珠模拟器零售价39.95美元
and uh, there's really not a whole lot else to talk about here,
然后，其他的话也没啥说的了
just, uh, the fact that this is a box, it exists.
这是个盒子，里面满满的
Oh yeah, there's some system requirement stuff there, but you know, pretty much...
对了，这里有系统要求。你懂的，简单来说
You just need a computer that is IBM compactable and have a game port.
你的电脑得是IBM兼容机，并且有一个游戏摇杆接口
Because inside the box, you can see here, is actually plug into a
因为开箱后，你会发现这东西是需要接到
typically like a sound card, game port or whatever you have had a game port installed.
游戏摇杆接口上面，声卡之类的扩展卡上应该有相关接口
So you know, that attaches to a keyboard.
当然，控制器本体是需要固定在键盘上的
So these are the controllers themselves, um...
而说到控制器本身呢
Pretty basic, very flimsy, plasticly kind of things, with crappy buttons.
它们很基础，塑料感觉很容易被碰坏，按钮手感很差
They're really, really filmsy.
质量真的不是太好
But anyway, this is kind of a cheap product, so I guess that make scene.
不过呢，毕竟廉价产品，质量差些很正常
This sort of slide underneath your keyboard.
底下的平板是滑进键盘底下的
And it will typically come with a piece of Velcro?
应该控制器两侧会有尼龙搭扣吧
To attach one side of the keyboard, in the other sides to
用来和键盘的一侧固定好，防止控制器滑动，因为它们经常会这样
these keep from sliding around, because these do sliding around.
I just use something else, like typically, those 3M mounting strips.
我用些别的好了，诸如3M固定胶带
We'll take a closer look at this in a monent,
一会我们再详细说明
but let's, uh, actually look inside the box here.
现在我们看看盒子里还有啥吧
Because, well, you got, of cource, the software.
当然，软件是最重要的
The configuration software and the Full Tilt! Pinball on this CD-ROM right here,
这张光盘里刻有配置软件和Full Tilt! Pinball游戏
at least in this America version.
至少美版光盘是这样的
A quick start guide for the pinball controller, which is a...
还有弹珠控制器的快速使用指南，简单来说
Yeah, you pretty much just plug it in,
你先将其插到电脑里
and then calibrate it like a joystick in the Windows 95.
然后在Windows 95下按游戏摇杆校准即可
And the... then there's a stuff for a... yeah, the Full Tilt! Pinball.
当然，这里也有一些和游戏有关的文字
I would be curious to find out in the development, like, what made them do this?
我想知道他们开发时的轶事，比如说，他们为啥要开发这个？
I know there were a ton of pinball games back in the day.
当年可是有很多的弹珠游戏啊
Like, for example, there's another one that you can get with it.
比如说，这广告里说的游戏
This is by the people that made Crystal Caliburn, say pinball table.
这是开发Crystal Caliburn的那帮人搞出来的弹珠台
Or uh, I think this is just a table.
好吧，应该就是弹珠台吧
Yeah, it comes with a CD-ROM called Loony Labyrinth.
而且，随弹珠台也会送来一张Loony Labyrinth游戏光盘
There were so many PC pinball games back then. It was ridiculous.
那个年代有很多的弹珠游戏，就很离谱
So I guess it make scene that, you know, it would enough of a niche market to make this.
所以我觉得，当时在这方面有市场，他们就做了
But, it still just so odd to me.
当然，这对我而言还是很奇怪
Inside, you also get the, the same quick guide or whatever, in a bunch of other languages.
盒子里还有很多其他语言的快速使用指南
A warranty card, some other warranty stuff.
一张保修卡，其他的保修相关
And a Thrustmaster product catalog.
还有一个Thrustmaster产品目录
Yeah, here are the stuff they would made back in the day.
里面写的是当时公司所生产的东西
They did all sort of really strange little devices.
每个东西都有一些怪异
Mostly having to do with racing and flight, as you can see here.
如你所见，大多和赛车和飞行模拟有关
But, this is another one that I actually want to get a hold of sometimes.
但是，这个东西我是很想收一个的
This is Pro Play Golf.
这个是Pro Play Golf（大师高尔夫）
And it let you play a golf game with a actual kind of putter thing,
貌似这玩意可以让你用真正的高尔夫球杆去玩
注：高尔夫中，putter指轻击球杆
You will see a lot of different um, I don't know, place to have a virtual golf swing.
你会在很多地方看到模拟高尔夫游戏，你可以在那里"挥杆"
模拟高尔夫示意图
OK, I just give you a little bit more on the idea of what's going on here.
好的，给大家详细介绍一下这个设备
Just a closer shot. Isn't this lovely?
先拉个近景，看上去挺好的吧
But yeah, here's the non-clicky kind of simulate a click, a kind of button.
但是呢，按下按钮时发出的声音是模拟出来的
Actually, when I take it apart, and then show you what actually goes on for the tilt control.
当然，拆开来就能看到这玩意是如何侦测倾斜的
So inside here is actually a pretty straightforward as the button itself.
里面呢，关于按钮本身倒也够直接的
You can actually see the switch there, which...
你可以看到这里的开关
You know, it's not the same kind of clicky metallic quality
你看啊，里面的按钮跟街机和弹珠台用的
that you could find in the arcade machine or really, pinball machine like micro switches.
有金属弹簧的微动按钮不完全一样
I does a least click a little, it just feels really cheap.
确实有点咔哒声音，就是感觉很廉价
And then these right here, you have these which control bumping and tilting.
而这俩光学传感器就是用来侦测撞击和倾斜的
You know, when you're moving around, or you bump in... either direction, really.
就是说，当你移动它的时候，或者你在撞击它的时候
Then this little guy here will react,
这个小玩意会跟着移动
and kind of finger out what you're doing as you move
然后判断出你的移动方向之类
and if you do too much, it till the table.
如果你移动幅度过大，他就告诉程序要倾斜了
Which does did work, kind of similar to what real pinball table does.
确实，和真实弹珠台的工作原理类似
Again, just much cheaper. And these are just really flimsy plasticky things.
不过就这脆塑料玩意更加廉价罢了
And I feel like if I touch them too much,
总觉得我再摸的话，这玩意会被我捏碎，碎片溅我一脸
they just going to explode, and give me shrapnel damage.
But yeah, let's go ahead and take a look at this things and action.
不过呢，该上机体验它了
I guess I should put it back together first.
在这之前还得给装回去
I know it's finally time to install these things,
现在该安装这个东西到键盘了
to put it on the Packard Bell keyboard that I use lately 'cause nostalgia.
为了怀旧，我这几天正使用这个Packard Bell键盘
And yeah, this is literally a simple, a whole manage is.
当然，安装这玩意还是很容易的
You just slide under there, and there you go.
只要将其滑到键盘底下就行了
You also put it on the other side.
另一侧同理
Like I said, it slides around. There's nothing that actually attach to anything.
不过我之前说过，这东西会滑来滑去的，毕竟没有固定
So you really do need something in order to take care of that.
所以说，我们确实需要某种东西来解决它
What I use actually, these little poster strips.
我这里就用这些海报用胶带了
So, I can use anything obviously, Velcro will work too,
当然，用其他的东西也成，尼龙搭扣也行
but these come off, without leaving sticky crappy residue.
但这些胶带脱落的时候，不会有黏黏糊糊的残留
And they keep these things in place. You just put on there.
而且固定得也很好，放上去就行了
That stick is on your keyboard. And that's pinball like, I suppose.
控制器就贴在键盘上了，这就更像是真正弹珠台的操作方式吧
Doesn't feel anything like the actual click of a real pinball table.
不过并没有真正弹珠台按钮按下去的咔嗒声
But that's OK! We're gonna try it anyway!
不过这是小问题，咱接着看吧
And as you can see here hopefully, in the control panel of the gaming option
如你所见，这是Win 95/98 版的游戏控制器设置
for Windows 95 or 98, in this case, you select it as a regular 2-axis, 4-button joystick.
你要将其设置为普通的2轴4按钮的游戏摇杆
And yeah, you can test it out and, try the motion, axes things there.
当然，你也可以测试一下移动侦测，两个轴之类的
So that's cool.
还行吧
And there's actually two different functions for each buttons.
而且每个按钮能映射两个功能
Like, you press it halfway, it'll press one button.
比如，轻按它相当于按下一个按钮
And press it all the way it get two, er, there are two buttons for the button.
而一直按下去的话，相当于按下两个按钮了
I guess that's for like doing things like, uh, swings, hits and whatnot.
我感觉这是为了模拟摇摆，撞击啥的
And of course, you also got the Thrustmaster Wizzard configuration things here
当然，这里还有控制器的配置软件
which, you don't actually need to use.
你基本没必要用这个
Useless you're using a game or playing a game that
除非你玩的游戏没有直接适配它
doesn't necessarily support this thing out of box.
Full Tilt! Pinball does. But if you have other game like come with preconfigured stuff
Full Tilt! Pinball 适配，但要是其他有特定配置的游戏
like 3DO Ultra Pinball, Crystal Caliburn... whatever, I really don't know what was it.
诸如 3DO Ultra Pinball, Crystal Caliburn... 等会，我刚才要想什么
Full Tilt! Pinball, for some reason...
而对于Full Tilt! Pinball来说......
Basically this is a keyboard interpreter for the thing.
基本上这东西相当于将其转换为键盘指令
So if you wanted to, you could actually map this stuff to keyboard commands
所以，你也可以把控制器的按钮映射为其他的键盘按钮
in order to make it work with stuff that doesn't made for the joystick.
以让那些自身没适配的游戏能使用这个设备玩
So let's go ahead and try Full Tilt! Pinball here. Because that's what it comes with.
现在，我们玩 Full Tilt! Pinball 吧，毕竟附带游戏
Let's do Space Cadet, as well as the Skulduggery
咱先玩太空军校生，以及后面那俩，不过还是先玩军校生吧
and the Dragon's Keep. But we'll try Space Cadet.
And yes, there are two other tables that goes along Space Cadet.
没错，这玩意附带的不仅有太空军校生哦，还有两个
注：BV1LW411R7UV 你玩过的三维弹球居然只是试玩版？ @ LGR & voodooman
Did you know that?  I did!  'Cause Maxis.
怪异的知识又增加了呢
Alright, so what we're doing here is go to enable joystick.
好的，这里先把游戏摇杆选项打开
And when I first tried this, it didn't work,
我第一次用的时候，它不工作
because it actually has to be given the ID of one.
因为控制器本应该被分配的编号是1
The Thrustmaster Wizzard program won't work either unless the joystick is mapped...
而 Thrustmaster Wizzard 软件是不会工作的，除非控制器被分配的
to ID 1, if it's like ID 2 or 3 or something, it's not gonna work. So just make sure that is that.
编号是1，而要是2或3的话，它就不会工作。刚我也说过了
Yeah, this looks pretty good.
好的，看上去很好
Pinball Wizzard Controller.
点击这个按钮
It might worked, that thing is sensitive as far as the tilt controls.
应该是在工作，而且倾斜侦测过于灵敏
It's like it's bumping the table at all time.
看上去弹珠台一直在被碰撞
It's not even touching anything.
我甚至啥都没碰
That table is like an earthquake!
好像弹珠台正在经历地震
I will say though, that the buttons are themselves were surprisingly better than
有一说一，按钮的手感比我想象的劣质手感好得太多了
you might imagine feeling how flimsy they are, just on their own.
But I mean it, you know...
真的是这样
Oh man, It's like playing pinball, it's pretty cool.
天啊，像是在玩真正的弹珠台，厉害了
Somehow I think I turned down the sound effects, I don't entirely sure how that happens.
不知为何，我好像把音效调低了，完全不知道为啥就降低了
My word, I suck at this even more.
天哪，拿这玩意玩得更差
So here is what I am talking about this far is like,
我想再说一下这事，我啥也没碰，弹珠台就在不行地被碰撞
I'm not touching anything and the table is bumping.
I don't know how well that showing up.
我也不知该怎样演示
But yeah, if I tilt it,
不过，我要真要触发倾斜的话
I mean, it really does work. At least it kinda works.
没错，倾斜侦测有效，至少看上去是这样
The problem being... I mean, the bumping is really good.
问题是...... 当然，碰撞模拟功能真挺好的
That's neat.
挺好的功能
But it does tilt, you know, pretty easily, so...
但是，倾斜侦测太容易触发了
OK, gonna try with one more game here. This is Balls of Steel.
好的，再试这款游戏，名称为 Balls of Steel
And it actually mapped to the keyboard control and doesn't support,
这款游戏是用键盘控制的，不支持摇杆啥的
like joystick or... whatever.
This is... So, let's try this out.
这就很......现在来试试吧
And it do crap.
然而基本没用
That's great.
:-(
OK. So obviously the thing is working.
好吧，控制器确实在工作
Like it's mapped to the keyboard.
也被映射到键盘按键上了
I guess that's typing thing.
看上去有点像在打字
That's typing things, so that's fine.
确实在打字，工作良好
But when I gonna play it.
可我要玩游戏的话
And it's mapped to the proper controls and everything.
尽管我已经映射好按键，配置好控制设定了
It's a different story.
它还是没法用
Nothing happens.
啥也没发生
I don't even know why.
我都不知道在干什么
So uh, that kinda sucks.
有点差劲
I was totally given up, but that's kind of a, uh, I even don't know what I am doing.
我刚想收起来，可是呢......我也不知我在想什么
So, let's try this.
无论如何，试试这个吧
It should be fun.
应该会挺有趣的
Well, that turns.
好吧，这是转弯
Uh, that moves forward.
这是前进
That shoots.
这是射击
And see, turing... I can totally do this!
演示一下转弯——我能搞死这俩！
They're shooting each other!
他们正自相残杀！
Come on! That's right, suck it! Zombies!
快点，把这些僵尸都干掉！
This is the future guys. I'm telling 'ya.
同志们，这就是游戏界的未来的发展方向啊
SuperBart：指体感游戏
Gonna turn left, since the right doesn't work.
现在左转，因为右转按键无法工作
GO FORWARD!
给我往前走啊！
Oh, this is way better than pinball.
没错，这比玩弹珠台好多了
Oh crap, what shoots?
天哪，谁在打我？
I forgot.
我给忘了
I think that does, sort of.
我觉得应该能行
That's right!
好极了！
I wanna beat this level!
我要通了这关！
Oh, it can be the greatest things.
没错，这么玩真的很好
And I think I can just run through it.
我觉得我就直接通关吧
Oh man.
天哪
Here we go. Oh, I almost had it for a second.
继续，貌似刚才走神了一下
This is got to be what this actually made for.
这才是控制器本来的用途吧（误）
Don't let the Imp see me!
别让小鬼看见我!
He's in the corner! Oh, how do I open things?
它在角落里！天哪，怎么打开啊？
Here it is!
终于打开了！
Yeah!
ヽ(＾Д＾)ﾉ
Thrustmaster Wizzard Pinball Controller, ten star out of five!
Thrustmaster Wizzard 弹珠控制器, 双倍五星好评!
Thank you for watching LGR Oddware.
感谢收看本期LGR志异
听写+翻译：SuperBart  样式参考fpsluozi@github  原作者LGR发布于2014-2-28
赞助原作者：https://www.patreon.com/LazyGameReviews
字幕下载：https://github.com/BenderBolg/Subtitles
上传给LGR：https://github.com/BenderBolg/LGR_Chinese_Subtitle